Division of Nutritional Sciences Cooperative Extension Nutrition Program Records, 1940-2005.
Division of Nutritional Sciences Cooperative Extension Nutrition Program Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Division of Nutritional Sciences Cooperative Extension Nutrition Program Records, 1940-2005.
29-4-2733
Cornell Cooperative Extension.Division of Nutritional Sciences.
14.9 cubic ft.
Reports, Publications, Manuals, Correspondence, Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publications and other printed material from the Division, including DNS ALERT. Nutrition curriculum and policy material concerning Extension in the Department of Food and Nutrition in the NYS College of Home Economics in the 1950's and 1960's and later in the Department of Human Nutrition and Food in the College of Human Ecology, 1969-1974. Also 4-H projects, newsletters, Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program (EFNEP) material and various other programs within the Division of Nutritional Sciences which was formed in 1974. Includes photographs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications and other printed material from the Division, including DNS ALERT.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Cooperative Extension.; Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program (U.S.)
Subjects:
Nutritional science--Study and teaching.; Nutrition extension work--New York (State); 4-H clubs--New York (State); Children--Nutrition.; Aging--Nutritional aspects.; Nutrition policy.; Curriculum planning--New York (State)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also collections #21-24-3292, Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program Records; #21-24-1975, Cornell University Cooperative Extension Records; and #29-1-3247, Division of Nutritional Sciences Records for related material.
SERIES LIST
Box 1: 4-H and Youth, Adult Food and Nutrition 1950-1969
Box 2: Programming For Adults 1970-1979
Box 3: Programming For Adults 1980-1991
Box 4: Efforts for Youth 1970-1991
Box 5: K-12 Nutrition Strand, K-6 Nutrition Comes Alive 1969-1982
Box 6: Nutrition Comes Alive, Samples K.1, 3 in 1982
Box 7: Nutrition Comes Alive, Samples 4.5, 6 in 1982
Box 8: Revised Nutrition Comes Alive, Nutrition for Life 1985-1988
Box 9: In Process Archives for Extension Efforts for Youth
Box 10: News Notes, Food Services Management, DNS Alert, Perspectives 1955-1986
Box 11: DNS Alert Newsletters 1984-1990
Box 12: DNS Alert Newsletters 1993-1995
CONTAINER LIST
- Title
  - Box 1: 4-H and Youth, Adult Food and Nutrition 1950-1969
  - Inventory, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Youth and Adult Food and Nutrition Programming by Extension Faculty, College of Home Economics Department of Food and Nutrition
  - Overview of Extension Programming, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Historical Documents (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cornell Reading Courses (Includes DomEcon cake), 1912-1918
    - News Bulletin-Home Economics Reminder "Nutrition First Research Established at College", 1926
    - War Emergency Bulletins, 1942-1943
    - Cornell Countryman Historical commentary, 1976
  - Section A: Status of College and Nutrition from 1960-1969
  - President's Committee on College of Home Economics (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings on Nutritional Status: 5th Institute, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photos, Newspaper Articles (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Reorganization of Extension
    Faculty Photos and Activities
    A Visit With Prof. Emeritus Catherine Personius: Div. Newsletter Interview (Oral Tape Available in Archives)
  - Section B: 4-H Youth Projects, Dept. of Food and Nutrition
  - 1) Combines Training Information and 4-H Project Materials
  - Food: Let's Begin and ABC's of Food (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Food-Let's Explore (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Breakfast is Ready (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fruit Delights (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Time For Lunch (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adventures in Dinner (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bake A Better Cake (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 4-H Pie Time (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 4-H Yeast Breads (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Let's Have a Party (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tips for Waitresses (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 2) Specialized 4-H Training/Activities
  - Let's Eat Game: Complement to Food, Let's Begin (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 4-H Canning (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 4-H Outdoor Cookery (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Safety in the Kitchen (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Food What's For: Nutrition For Teens (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Adventures in Meats and Meat the Decision (Teens) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Public Presentations/ Demonstrations (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Printed Bulletins to Supplement 4-H Programs (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Section C: Adult Extension Programs, Dept. of Food and Nutrition
  - An Interpretative Notebook of Teaching Materials in the Public Service Program Prepared by Staff in Former Department of Food and Nutrition (Box 1, Folder 26A)
    - Low Income Audiences
    - Research Findings on Vulnerable Groups
    - Weight Control
    - Food Additives and Safety
    - Guides To Food Buying
    - Sound Nutrition Education
    - Teenage Nutrition
    - News And Views Newsletters, 1968-1969
  - Program Information for Home Bureau/Extension Home Economists (Box 1, Folder 26B)
  - Meal Management Series (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Main Dishes For One Dish Meals, 1950
    - Short Cuts in Meal Making, 1952
    - Quick Hearty Suppers, 1954
    - Broiler Meals, 1957
    - Getting The Most From Your Oven, 1960
  - Choosing and Using Vegetables, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Choices from the Meat Counter, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - What Moderns Should Know About Baking Ingredients, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Mini Lessons (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Low Calorie Refreshments, 1954
    - Freezing with Confidence, 1961
  - Calorie Sense and Nonsense and Changing Attitudes about Weight Control Slide Set, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Reaching Out to Minority Audiences, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - State Fair Exhibit Photos "Controlling Your Weight", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - RDA Revision, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Cornell" Bread-Developed by Prof. Clive McCay, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Food and Nutrition Bulletins, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Food and Nutrition Bulletins, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Food and Nutrition Bulletins, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Food and Nutrition Bulletins, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Section D: Documents Describing Activities of Dept. of Institution Management which merged in 1969 with the Dept. of Food and Nutrition to become Dept. of Nutrition and Food
  - "History of the Department of Institution Management 1925-1969" by Bernice Hopkins, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Examples of Printed Bulletins Prepared by Extension Faculty in Department of Institution Management, 1960-1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Box 2: Programming For Adults 1970-1979
  - Inventory: Adult Education, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Overview of Adult Food and Nutrition Extension Programming" by Martha C. Mapes (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Section A: Status of Nutrition Education, Food, Hunger 1970
  - The Hunger USA Debate (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McGovern Committee Report (US Senate Subcommittee) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NY State Health Dept. Bureau of Nutrition, John Browe MD "Nutrition in the 70's", 1970's (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reports on White House Conference, early nutrition education efforts: Selected Journals of Nutrition Education, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Public Hearings (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Testimony by Robert Choate Senate Commerce Committee, 1970-1973
    - Choate Presentation: National Association of Broadcasters, 1972
    - Public Hearings on Organic Foods, 1972
  - Working papers Department Human Nutrition and Food Staffing needs, Philosophy/Policy (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Working paper on nutrition education by national committee (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Section B: Inservice and In-depth Training for County Extension Agents
  - EFNEP Programming (See Brink history for other EFNEP), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Puerto Rican Food Habits, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Behind the Nutrition Headlines: Food Safety, Food Additives, Nutrition, and the Pill, Recent Nutrition Books, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Food Service in Child Care Programs, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Early Childhood Education, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Nutrition Education for the Elderly, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Nutrition Now: New Resources, Nutrition Labeling, Facts about Current Concerns (Cholesterol and Vitamin E, Alternate Food Patterns, Vegetarianism and TVP), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Indepth Week Course: Overweight: Background Information, Current Research and Implications for Field Work, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Nutrition Education Programs for the Elderly, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Nutrition, Growth, and Reproduction: Reducing the Risks for Mothers and Children (Open to outside professionals), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Indepth Week Course: Process Evaluation of Nutrition Education Programs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Indepth Week Course: Food Policy Educational Programs in New York State, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Indepth Week Couse: Obesity and Overweight: Current Issues and Programs, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Future Outlook for Plant Foods (Guests: NE+ Food Editors), Food Preservation Updates, Samples of annual event, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Section C: Published Extension Resources
  - Printed Resources (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Annotated Bibliography of Educational Materials HNF
    - Nutrition For Those with Special Needs
    - How Children Learn About Foods
    - Early Childhood Nutrition Program
    - Series of Handouts on infant nutrition
    - Calories and Activity flip chart
  - Printed Resources (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Nutrition Labels, Terms You Should Know About
    - A Guide To Nutritive Value
    - Think Microwave
    - Positive Living In The Senior Years
    - Cut Food Costs When You Shop
    - College Publications, 1973
  - Printed Resources (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Food For Health: The Carbohydrate Connection
      Overview and set of point of purchase leaflets
  - Spanish Resources (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Foods For Health: The Puerto Rican Food Wheel
    - Food Safety Tips
  - Audio Visual promotionals (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Brochure: Cornell Nutrition Slide Sets
    - Nutritional Labeling
    - Nutritional Labeling: Whats In It For You?
    - Natural Foods: Good, Bad And Different
    - Energy: Our Food and Our Needs
    - Protein: What Is It? And Iron: How Big A Problem
    - Films
      - Food Preservation of food
      - Pressure Canning Update
  - Slide sets in sleeves (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Section D: Benchmark DNS Extension Planning Documents
  - Regional Program Development Meetings: Eating for Health Maintenance, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Overview of Extension Program Resources and Organization Chart, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Extension Planning Process and Evaluation, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Section E: Outlook for US Extension
  - Draft Statement: Extension Task Force and Technical Panel: Six areas of activity. Note P. 5 Future Thrusts, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - National Food Review, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Section F: Current Issues and Trends: Background for DNS Planning
  - Human Ecology Forum Issues with nutrition focus, 1972, 1973, 1976, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Biennial Nutrition Institute (Sample programs) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Public Hearings in New York, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Public Hearings concerning Childrens Television Advertising, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Box 3: Programming For Adults 1980-1991
  - Inventory, 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Overview: "DNS Extension Programming for Adults in the 1980s" by Martha C. Mapes (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Section A: Training Opportunities for Field Staff
  - InDepth Week Course: Nutrition Education Moves Forward, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Inservice By-Mail: Nutrition A Holistic Approach, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - InDepth Week Course: Dietary Guidance, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Inservice: Computer Pilot Workshop, A Tool for Programming, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Inservice: Moving Towards Fitness I, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Public meeting for nutrition professionals Cosponsered by Day Public Relatoins NY, NY, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Inservice: Moving Towards Fitness II, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Inservice: Food Preservation Workshop, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Inservice: Moving Towards Fitness III Building Nutrition Fitness Programs, Guests including Dr. Reuben Andres, Johns Hopkins, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - InDepth Week Course: Nutrition-Concepts, Controversies, Uncertainties, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Inservice: Food Preservation Workshop, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Inservice: Marketing Nutrition on TV, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Inservice: Getting Ready for Action, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Using Theories and Models to Promote Program Implementation
    - Nutrition Education To Promote helath and reduce Risk of Chronic Disease
    - Preparation for Parenthood
    - Managing Resources for Healthful Eating
    - Revitalizing the Nutrition Education Network
    - Planning and Evaluation Using a Communication Approach
    - Program Emphasis and Outcome Indicators
  - InDepth Week Course: Basic Nutrition Concepts for Interpreting Dietary Guidelines, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Inservice: Nutrition Fitness and Heart Health Prelude to Take Charge Program, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Inservice: Take Charge, Educator's Guide Training, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Inservice: Take Charge, Participant's Guide and Nutrition Education at the Worksite, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Inservice: Nutrition and Cancer Prevention, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Includes 18 page annotated bibliography
  - Inservice: Food Preservation Update, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Inservice: Take Charge (Oct 9-11), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Inservice: Take Charge Revised, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Section B: DNS Published Educational Resources
  - Annotated Bibliographies of DNS Educational Materials, 1976-2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - DNS published resources containing: (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - The Nutrient Guide - 2 parts
    - Dietary Guidelines, 1985,1990
    - Carbohydrates: The Inside Story
  - DNS published resources containing: (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - The Sodium Content of Food
    - Sodium Food, Sodium Health: Packet of Information
    - A Woman's Guide To Calcium
  - DNS published resources: (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - You Should Know About Added Nutrients, 1982-10
    - You Should Know About Food Colors, 1982-10
    - You Should Know About Nonsugar Sweeteners, 1982-10
    - You Should Know About Sweeteners, 1981-11, 1982-10
    - You Should Know About Flavors, 1981-12, 1982-02, 1982-10
    - You Should Know About Bakery Products, 1982-03, 1982-05
    - You Should Know About Caffeine, 1981-12
    - You Should Know About Thickeners, 1982-04, 1982-10
    - You Should Know Advertising Claims, 1982-05, 1982-10
    - You Should Know About Preservatives, 1981-11
    - You Should Know About Food Ingredients - Sugar and Health, 1982-01
    - You Should Know About Food Ingredients - Saccharin, 1982-07
    - You Should Know About Food Ingredients - Sorbitol and Mannitol, 1982-07
    - You Should Know About Food Ingredients - Regulating Food Advertisements, 1982-08
    - Shopper's Guide to Commonly Used Food Ingredients, 1982-04
  - Published resources containing:: (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - The Basics of Breast Feeding: A Mother's Guide
    - Nourishing and Nurturing Two Year Olds
  - DNS published resources containing: (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Moving Towards Fitness - Exhibit Quiz
    - Nutrition and Exercise
    - Lean on Beef
    - Revitalize Your Recipes For Better Health, Revised
  - DNS published resource: Three ring notebook (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Taking Charge Of Your Heart Health: Participants Guide Revised Edition and Four Step Program, 1991-1992
  - Taking Charge Of Your Heart Health: County programs and Evaluation (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - The New York Lean Computer Program (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Section C: Special New York and NE Studies
  - Lean on Beef- by Martha Mapes and Laura Winters (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Light and Easy" (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Snack Wisely- by Barbara Schirmer and Martha Mapes (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Feeding your Baby" - slide set script- by Christine Olson and Jill Randell (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - A Health Education Experience for 9-13 year olds Focusing on Food- A Consumer Issue- by Barbara Fry, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - For Those with Special Needs: Pregnant Women, infants, young children- Developed by Jill Randell, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Nutrition for those with Special Needs- Pregnant Women, Infants, young children- tapes- developed by Christine Olson, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Nutrition, Growth and Reproduction: Reducing the Risks for Mothers and Infants- Developed by Christine Olson and Martha Mapes, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "Food Waste as an Individual Concern" by Martha Mapes and Barbara Stewart, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "Fun with Fruits" Leaders guide and Member's guide, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Bake Cakes That Count- by Martha Mapes and Mary Lee Bourbeau, 1980-11 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Early Childhood Nutrition Program- Nutrition Activities: Preschoolers and Parents- Spanish version, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Early Childhood Nutrition Program- Educator's Guide- Food Experiences for Young Children, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Early Childhood Nutrition Program- Nutrition Activities: Preschoolers and Parents, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Early Childhood Nutrition Program- Early Childhood Educator's: Nutrition Handbook, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Contemporary Pies for a Healthier Diet- 4-H Leader's Guide- by Martha Mapes, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "You Should Know About Food Ingredients" by Patricia Thonney and Carole Bisogni, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Food Ingredient Information for Consumers: The Design and Evaluation of "You Should Know About Food Ingredients"- by Carole Bisogni, Patricia Thonney, Glenna Kophen, 1982-12 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Good Nutrition: An Investment in Your Family's Future- by Ardyth Gillespie, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Development of a Computerized Data File for Food Ingredients- Final Report- by Carole Bisogni and Patricia Thonney, 1984-06 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Guide to Using the Food Ingredient Data File- Appendix C to Development of a Computerized Data File for Food Ingredients- Final Report- by Carole Bisogni and Patricia Thonney, 1984-06 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - The Text of the Food Ingredient Data File- Supplement A to Development of a Computerized Data File for Food Ingredients- Final Report- by Carole Bisogni and Patricia Thonney, 1984-06 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - "Make up your Mind About Alcohol" - training manual for teen discussion leaders- by Martha Mapes and Gayle Leitch, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - NYLEAN- New York Learning About Eating, Activity and Nutrition, 1987-07 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Groundwater Contamination: Working in Partnership with Communities by Nancy Ostiguy, Susan Turnquist, Carole Bisogni, June MacDonald, Janet Fitchen, 1989-12 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "Be Somebody! Stay out of Trouble with Alcohol- 7th and 8th grade training manual by Martha Mapes, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "Take Charge of Your Heart Health"- Handbook- Developed by Martha Mapes, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - "Take Charge of Your Heart Health"- Educator's Guide- Developed by Martha Mapes, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - "Take Charge of Your Heart Health"- Educator's Guide- Developed by Martha Mapes, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - "Take Charge of Your Heart Health"- Educator's Guide- Developed by Martha Mapes, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - "Take Charge of Your Heart Health"- additional material (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Private Food Assistance in NYS- Challenges for the 1990s, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Food and Nutrition Basics- handouts, 1990-1999 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - "Be Somebody! Stay Out of Trouble with Alcohol"- Part I, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - "Be Somebody! Stay Out of Trouble with Alcohol"- Part II by Martha Mapes, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - "A Disfrutar con los Alimentos", 1992 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - 4-H Food and Nutrition Communicator, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Taking Care of Two- Nutrition for Moms and Babies- English and Spanish, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - "Supermarket Nutrition Education in NYS", 1993-03 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Hispanics in Metropolitan New York: Perceptions and Practices Related to the Quality, Safety, and Healthfulness of Fish and Seafood- by Stephanie Weinstein and Carole Bisogni- Final Report, 1995-06 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Learnings from the ES/WIC Projects- Building Blocks for Toddlers (BBT) and Healthy Families, 1993-1997-04 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Immigrants and the Community, 2004-11 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Immigrants and the Community Farmworkers with Families, 2005-04 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Immigrants and the Community Former Farmworkers, 2005-09 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Immigrants and the Community Perspectives- by- Max Pfeffer and Pilar Parra, 2005-10 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - An Analysis Of programming In Nutrition And Physical Activity, Sabbatical Report By Martha C. Mapes, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - VideoTex and TeleTex: An Opportunity For Educators, Cornell Cooperative Extension Conference, 1984-01 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - New York State Nutrition: The State Of The State (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Nutritional Health Of School,Children In Upstate New York (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Making Food Safe: Food Safety Is Everyone's Business, A Policy Education Program- NE Network Project (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Section D: Changes In Extension Personnel and Direction
  - DNS Extension Faculty- Time Allocation (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - DNS Extension Plans For Work, Trends And Challenges, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - DNS Extension Plans Of Work, 1988-1991,1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - New York State Financial Situation, 1988,1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Section E: Cooperative Extension System: Background and Futuring Documents
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - The Ecology of Human Health - M.Devine
    - Centre For Excellence Overture
    - Liaison with Dept. of Health: Pros And Cons
    - DNS Nutrition Newsletters: Selected Volumes
    - 10th Anniversary
    - Samples: Nutrition Institutes
  - College of Human Ecology Extension Futuring (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Home Economics The Third Generation: A Plan For The 80s
    - Priority issues and statewide issue committees
  - Cornell Campus (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Report of the Commission: Future Of The Cornell Cooperative Extension System, 1987-03
  - (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - NYS Council on Food and Nutrition Policy: Five Year Food and Nutrition Plan, 1988-1992
    - Licensure Options Law, 1992
  - USDA Extension Service (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Food And Nutrition: The Link Between Health And Agriculture: Directions For The Cooperative Extension System, 1986
      Supported By ECOP and USDA, written by C.Bisogni, P. Thonney, M.Nesheim and Expert Advisory Panel
    - Wolf And Peterkin, Dietary Guidelines: The USDA Perspective, 1984
    - Dietary Guideline Series For Consumers, 1986
    - New Directions For The Cooperative Extension System By Denzel O. Clegg Assoc. Administration Extension Service Paper, 1987-11
  - United States Dept. Of Health and Human Services/National Research C. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - The Surgeon General's Report: Excerpts Nutrition and Health, 1988
    - National Research Council: Diet And Health, 1989
    - Perspective: Review of Dietary Recommendations, 1988
  - Trends related to food and nutrition concerns (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Box 4: Efforts for Youth 1970-1991